Guide to the Rudolf Carnap Papers, 1904-2007 ASP.1974.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Notes and Correspondence: Probability, Mathematics, Publishers, UCLA Administrative, and Lecture Notes, 1927-1970; XII.
  - Notes on Mathematics and Correspondence with Publishers, 2.
    - Meiner, 1967-1970 (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Meiner, Felix, 1931 (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Nymphenburger Verlag, 1970 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Open Court, 1965-1970 (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - Reidel (Synthese), 1965-1970 (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - Routledge & Kegan Paul Ltd., 1959-1970 (Box 85, Folder 22)
    - Scribner's: Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - Springer Verlag, 1970 (Box 85, Folder 24)
    - Springer Verlag, 1967-1969 (Box 85, Folder 25)
    - Springer, Material für Syntax, 1967-1968 (Box 85, Folder 26)
    - Springer Abrechnungen, 1967-1970 (Box 85, Folder 27)
    - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft, 1967-1968 (Box 85, Folder 28)
  - UCLA Administrative Documents, 3.
    - UCLA: Academic Freedom, 1950-1954 (Box 85, Folder 29)
    - UCLA Appointment, 1952-1964 (Box 85, Folder 30)
    - UCLA Bio-Bibliography, 1955-1967 (Box 85, Folder 31)
    - UCLA Committees: Promotion, PhD, 1958-1965 (Box 85, Folder 32)
    - UCLA Administrative General, 1959-1965 (Box 85, Folder 33)
    - UCLA Research Committee, 1955-1962 (Box 85, Folder 34)
    - UCLA Retirement, 1957-1964 (Box 85, Folder 35)
    - UCLA Meetings, 1961-1963 (Box 85, Folder 36)
    - UCLA Colleagues, 1958-1965 (Box 85, Folder 37)
    - UCLA Exam Questions, 1938-1958 (Box 85, Folder 38)
    - UCLA Department, Old, 1958-1961 (Box 85, Folder 39)
    - Positions in Philosophy, Other Universities, 1961 (Box 85, Folder 40)
    - Teacher Candidates, 1959 (Box 85, Folder 41)
    - Teaching Assistants, 1961-1962 (Box 85, Folder 42)
    - TP, Grades, 1956-1962 (Box 85, Folder 43)
    - UCLA Students, General, 1959 (Box 85, Folder 44)
    - UCLA Students, Recommendations, 1938, 1956-1960 (Box 85, Folder 45)
    - Champawat, Narayan, 1961-1969 (Box 85, Folder 46)
    - Cocchiarella, Nino, 1961-1963 (Box 85, Folder 47)
    - Colburn, Brooks, 1970 (Box 85, Folder 48)
    - Friedman, Joel, 1962-1969 (Box 85, Folder 49)
    - Kahane, Howard, 1959-1960 (Box 85, Folder 50)
    - Lauter, Herman A., 1960-1967 (Box 85, Folder 51)
    - Mathers, Ruth Anna, 1961-1962 (Box 85, Folder 52)
    - Neblett, William Richard, Jr., 1961-1964 (Box 85, Folder 53)
    - Pugh, Edward L., 1963 (Box 85, Folder 54)
    - Purtill, Richard L., 1960-1966 (Box 85, Folder 55)
    - Travis, Larry, 1956-1964 (Box 85, Folder 56)
    - Linguistics, Puhvel, Jaan, 1966 (Box 85, Folder 57)
    - Marschak, Jacob, Colloquium on the Application of Mathematics in the Social Sciences, 1960-1962 (Box 85, Folder 58)
    - UCLA Library Information, 1955-1961 (Box 85, Folder 59)
    - UCLA General: Survey, Book Lists, Lecture Listings, 1926-1962 (Box 85, Folder 60)
  - Lecture Notes, 4.
    - Notes on Semantics (Memo), 1966 (Box 85, Folder 61)
    - Adv. Symb. Logik, 1949-1964 (Box 85, Folder 62)
    - Introduction to Analytical Philosophy, 1936-1950 (Box 85, Folder 63)
    - Problems of Empiricism, 1939-1951 (Box 85, Folder 64)
    - Logical Foundations of Mathematics, 1932-1959 (Box 85, Folder 65)
    - History of Philosophy, Prag, (Item 1), 1929-1936 (Box 85, Folder 66a)
    - History of Philosophy, Prag, (Item 2), 1929-1936 (Box 85, Folder 66b)
    - Probability & Induction, 1937-1960 (Box 85, Folder 67)
    - Selected Problems, 1961-1962 (Box 85, Folder 68)
    - Semantics, 1937-1955 (Box 85, Folder 69)
    - Syntax, 1932-1951 (Box 85, Folder 70)
    - Probability, 1947-1954 (Box 85, Folder 71)
    - Semantics & Abstract Entities, 1949-1967 (Box 85, Folder 72)
    - Values, 1951-1959 (Box 85, Folder 73)
    - Notes for Psychology Meeting, Urbana, Prof. Miller, 1950 (Box 85, Folder 74)
- "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic" and Schilpp Replies: Ditto Material for Distribution, 1952-1965; XIII.
  This material represents mimeo copies of Carnap's writings intended for distribution, mainly his "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic" and "Replies" for the Schilpp volume The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap.
  - Formulas for Inductive Logic, 1961 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Formulas, Theoretical Concepts (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - The Methodological Character of Theoretical Concepts (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Semantics (Incomplete Parts), 1955-1960 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Probability and Induction (Incomplete), 1955 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Remarks on Physicalism and Related Topics: Discussions with Wilfrid Sellars, December 1954 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - The Concept of Degree of Order, May 1952 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Vorwort zum Aufbau, 1961 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Preface to 2nd edition of The Logical Foundation of Probability, 1962 (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - The Aim of Inductive Logic (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Probability and Content Measure (Second Version), 1963 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Axiom System for Inductive Logic: Corrections, 1965 (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Rudolf Carnap Bibliography, NSF, 1961 (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - Books on Philosophy of Science, 1960 (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography on Probability and Induction, 1955, 1960 (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography for Seminar Philosophy, Spring 1962 (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - Notes on Semantics (Complete), Bibliography, 1955, 1959 (Box 86, Folder 17)
  - Space-Time Topology, Logic §48, 1961 (Box 86, Folder 18)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Part III, (Item 1a), 1961 (Box 86, Folder 19a)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Part III, (Item 1b), 1961 (Box 86, Folder 19b)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Part IV, 1963 (Box 86, Folder 20)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Chapter 17, February 1965 (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - Empty file folder (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Loose Sections 17 & 18 (Start) (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Section 18 (Conclusion), 1964 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Section 19, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Ditto Masters: An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, Insertions, §16 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Ditto Masters: An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, §19, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Ditto Masters: An Axiom System of Inductive Logic, §17 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Formulas for "Aim" (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Items 1-11) (Box 87, Folder 9a)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Items 12-28) (Box 87, Folder 9b)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap: "Replies" (Box 87, Folder 14)
- Correspondence with Philosophy Authors, 1930-1970; XIV.
  These exchanges between Carnap and fellow philosophers cover mostly research and professional issues. The folders are arranged alphabetically by last name.
  - Apostel, Leo, 1952-1954 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Bartley, William Warren III, 1965-1969 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Benson, Arthur, 1961-1970 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Bernays, Paul, 1960-1964 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Beth, E.W., 1958-1961 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Blumberg, Albert E., 1962-1965 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Bocheński, Józef Maria, 1954-1960 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Bohnert, Herbert, 1961-1964 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Bohnert Manuscripts, 1961-1962 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Bressan, Aldo, 1959-1969 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Brown, J.M., 1968 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Bunge, Mario, 1961-1969 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Bynum, Terrell Ward, 1965-1968 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1968-1969 (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Church, Alonzo and Benson Mates, Belief Sentences, 1940-1963 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Cohen, Robert, 1957-1970 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - Cooley: Meine Lösungen zu den Aufgaben in seinem Logic Buch, 1945-1948 (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - Copi, Irving M., 1949-1963 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - Craig, William: Über Axiomatizability and Ramsey Sentence, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Creary, Lewis G., 1970 (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - Delius, Harald, 1964-1968 (Box 88, Folder 21)
  - Earman, John S., 1966 (Box 88, Folder 22)
  - Edwards, Paul, 1961-1967 (Box 88, Folder 23)
  - Essler, Wilhelm Karl, 1964-1970 (Box 88, Folder 24)
  - Feigl, Herbert: Positivism, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 25)
  - Feyerabend, Paul, 1957-1966 (Box 88, Folder 26)
  - Frege (Empty Folder) (Box 88, Folder 27)
  - Furth (Empty Folder) (Box 88, Folder 28)
  - Gardner, Martin, 1958-1965 (Box 88, Folder 29)
  - Gödel, Kurt, 1948, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 30)
  - Gortari, Eli (Artemisa) de, 1970 (Box 88, Folder 31)
  - Grünbaum, Adolf, 1955-1965 (Box 88, Folder 32)
  - Gullvåg, Ingemund, 1967-1969 (Box 88, Folder 33)
  - Hartley, Raymond E., 1957-1964 (Box 88, Folder 34)
  - Hempel, Carl Gustav, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 35)
  - Hoering, Walter, 1967-1970 (Box 88, Folder 36)
  - Hoo, Tzu-hua, 1944-1945 (Box 88, Folder 37)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1948-1949 (Box 88, Folder 38)
  - Hutten, Ernest H., 1954 (Box 88, Folder 39)
  - Jeffreys, Harold, 1940 (Box 88, Folder 40)
  - Kaplan, David, 1959-1963 (Box 88, Folder 41)
  - Kecskemeti, Paul, 1940-1955 (Box 88, Folder 42)
  - Kemeny: Semantics, 1954-1955 (Box 88, Folder 43)
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz, 1930 (Box 88, Folder 44)
  - Kraft, Victor, 1969-1970 (Box 88, Folder 45)
  - Krauth, Lothar, 1968-1969 (Box 88, Folder 46)
  - Kuhn, Thomas S., 1960-1962 (Box 88, Folder 47)
  - Lakatos, Imre, 1967-1968 (Box 88, Folder 48)
  - Laso, José Alvarez: Mexico, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 49)
  - Lazerowitz, Prof. Alice, Prof. Morris, 1968-1969 (Box 88, Folder 50)
  - Leijonhufvud, Axel, 1966-1967 (Box 88, Folder 51)
  - Leinfellner, Werner, 1962-1969 (Box 88, Folder 52)
  - Lewis, David K., 1967-1969 (Box 88, Folder 53)
  - Loehrich, Rolf R., 1951-1954 (Box 88, Folder 54)
  - Lorenzen, Paul, 1963-1965 (Box 88, Folder 55)
  - Luckenbach, Sidney A., 1966 (Box 88, Folder 56)
  - Lutman, Maria, 1935, 1940, 1962 (Box 88, Folder 57)
  - Marcovic, Mihailo, 1962-1964 (Box 88, Folder 58)
  - Marcuse, Herbert, Clippings, 1969 (Box 88, Folder 59)
  - Martin, Richard M., 1948, 1960-1969 (Box 88, Folder 60)
  - Mates, Benson, 1966 (Box 88, Folder 61)
  - Mathers, Bob, 1963-1970 (Box 88, Folder 62)
  - Matheson, Gordon, 1956-1966 (Box 88, Folder 63)
  - Mehlberg, Henry, 1959-1970 (Box 88, Folder 64)
  - Molina, Flores Nicolas, 1959-1962 (Box 88, Folder 65)
  - Molina, Flores Nicloas, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 66)
  - Montague, Richard, 1956-1966 (Box 88, Folder 67)
  - Moore, G.E., 1941 (Box 88, Folder 68)
  - Morandini, Michael, 1959-1967 (Box 88, Folder 69)
  - Morris, Charles, 1959-1962 (Box 88, Folder 70)
  - Morris, Charles: Bibliography for Encyclopedia, 1960-1966 (Box 88, Folder 71)
  - Morrison, Paul G., 1954-1963 (Box 88, Folder 72)
  - Mulder, H.L., 1963 (Box 88, Folder 73)
  - Myhill, John, 1951-1968 (Box 88, Folder 74)
  - Nagel, Ernest, 1946-1947, 1964-1967 (Box 88, Folder 75)
  - Nakhnikian, George, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 76)
  - Oppenheim, Paul, 1954 and 1968 (Box 88, Folder 77)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert: Clippings, 1948-1969 (Box 88, Folder 78)
  - Pasquinelli, Alberto, 1954-1963 (Box 88, Folder 79)
  - Patzig, Günther, 1966-1967 (Box 88, Folder 80)
  - Popper, Karl R., 1959-1964 (Box 88, Folder 81)
  - Prior, Arthur N., Gespräch, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 82)
  - Purtill, Richard L., 1966-1968 (Box 88, Folder 83)
  - Putnam, Hilary, 1958-1965 (Box 88, Folder 84)
- Language Systems, Semantics, Value Theory, Logical Modalities, 1932-1962; XV.
  This series contains material relating to language systems and semantics, as well as notes and correspondence discussing modal logic.
  - Lattice Theory, Letters to Quine, 1942, 1959-1960 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Ordered N-Tuple, 1957-1959 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Standardized Word-Language, 1938-1942 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Systems without Types, 1937-1938 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Intensions, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - L-Truth: Älteres, auch Gespräch mit Tarski, 1937-1939 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Terminology for Meanings and Expressions, especially with '-tor', 1941-1943 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Questions on Terminology of Semantics, 1932-1942 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Meaning Postulates (A-Concepts), 1954 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Theoretical Terms, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Ramsey-Sentence, Hempel's "A Theoretician's Dilemma", 1956 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - On Type Theory (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Optatives, Value Theory, 1958-1961 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Value Function V, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - General System of Modalities, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Identity of Intensions, 1962 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Seminar über Modalitäten, 1957-1962 (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Behmann: Modalität, 1953-1955 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Montague: Modalities, 1955 (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Über MFC, 1949 (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - Arthur Pap: Paradox über Belief Sentences, 1955 (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - Causal Modality and Nomology, 1941-1955 (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - Translation of Modalities, with Kalish, (Items 1-17), 1954-1955 (Box 89, Folder 23a)
  - Translation of Modalities, with Kalish (Items 18-27), 1954-1955 (Box 89, Folder 23b)
- Publications, Interviews, and Lectures Notes, 1903-1969; XVI.
  This series features mostly drafts of Carnap's writings, ranging from early attempts at drama writing around 1903 to drafts of his later publications in the 1960s. Included are also early lecture notes from Vienna and Prague, some interviews, plus related notes and correspondence.
  - Translation of Carnap's Aufbau by Rolf George, 1962-1969 (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - Probability and Content Measure, Feigl Festschrift, 1961-1966 (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - A Few Words to Philipp Frank for the Second Volume of Boston Studies, 1965 (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - "Variety, Analogy, and Periodicity in Inductive Logic": A Response to Achinstein, 1943, 1953, 1962-1963 (Box 89, Folder 27)
  - Remarks on Probability, Philosophical Studies, 1962, 1962-1963 (Box 89, Folder 28)
  - Supplementary Bibliography Probability II, 1962-1963 (Box 89, Folder 29)
  - Vorwort Aufbau, 1961-1962 (Box 89, Folder 30)
  - Kongress-Vortrag "The Aim of Inductive Logic", 1960-1961 (Box 89, Folder 31)
  - "On the Use of Hilbert's E-Operator in Scientific Theories," for Fraenkel Anniversary Volume, 1959-1961 (Box 89, Folder 32)
  - "Einführung in die symbolische Logik," 2.A., 1955-1968 (Box 89, Folder 33)
  - Notizen für "Theoretical Concepts" (Feigl-Band), 1953-1962 (Box 89, Folder 34)
  - "Statistical and Inductive Probability," Galois Institute, 1955-1956 (Box 89, Folder 35)
  - "An Outline of a Theory of Semantic Information," with Bar-Hillel, 1949-1963 (Box 89, Folder 36)
  - Zu McKinsey's Brief über mein Ms "Modalitäten", 1945 (Box 89, Folder 37)
  - "The Problem of a World Language", 1944 (Box 89, Folder 38)
  - Formalization of Logic, 1949 (Box 89, Folder 39)
  - "Introduction to Semantics," Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 89, Folder 40)
  - "Logical Foundations of the Unity of Science," Notes by Morris and Neurath, 1938 (Box 89, Folder 41)
  - English Translation of "Die logische Syntax der Sprache (Items 1-14)", 1934-1964 (Box 89, Folder 42a)
  - English Translation of "Die logische Syntax der Sprache (Items 15-28)" (Box 89, Folder 42b)
  - "Philosophy and Logical Syntax," Remarks and Revisions, 1935-1965 (Box 89, Folder 43)
  - Remarks on "Logical Syntax", 1934-1941 (Box 89, Folder 44)
  - "Remarks" on 19, 20, 21, 12, 1957-1966 (Box 89, Folder 45)
  - Rezensionen über andere Autoren, 1934 (Box 89, Folder 47)
    - Rezension der Logistik, 1930-1931 (Box 89, Folder 46)
  - Ms on Mind-Body-Dualism, 1955, 1966-1967 (Box 89, Folder 48)
  - Interview by Waren O. Hagstrom, 1961 (Box 89, Folder 50)
    - "Die Zukunft der Philosophie": Interview with Dr. Willy Hochkeppel, Bayerischer Rundfunk, 1964-1965 (Box 89, Folder 49)
  - Set theory, 1960-1961 (Box 89, Folder 51)
  - Ms "Prologue" für M. Bunge: "Semantische Antologie", 1957-1960 (Box 89, Folder 52)
  - "Theoretical Concepts in Science," Transcript, Santa Barbara Lecture (Items 1-8), 1959-1964 (Box 89, Folder 53a)
  - "Theoretical Concepts in Science," Santa Barbara Lecture (Item 9), 1959 (Box 89, Folder 53b)
  - "Theoretical Concepts in Science," Notes, 1958-1959 (Box 89, Folder 54)
  - "Three Approaches to Inductive Logic" (Items 1-2), 1956-1967 (Box 89, Folder 55a)
  - 4. The Structure Space (Items 3-6), 1957 and 1967 (Box 89, Folder 55b)
  - Alternative to "Three Approaches" (Items 7-14), 1956-1959 (Box 89, Folder 55c)
  - "Three Approaches to Inductive Logic" (Items 15-16) (Box 89, Folder 55d)
  - Zero Cases, 1956 (Box 89, Folder 56)
  - "On the Choice of an Inductive Method: A Reply to John W. Lenz.", 1956-1957 (Box 89, Folder 57)
  - "On the Use of Codified Language Systems in Logic", 1954 (Box 89, Folder 58)
  - "Summary: The Concept of Degree of Order", 1952 (Box 89, Folder 59)
  - "The Concept of Degree of Order in Inductive Logic" (Items 1-2), 1951-1952 (Box 89, Folder 60a)
  - "The Concept of Degree of Order in Inductive Logic" (Items 3-7), 1947 and 1951 (Box 89, Folder 60b)
  - "The Concept of Degree of Order in Inductive Logic" (Item 8) (Box 89, Folder 60c)
  - "Das System der Wissenschaften: Eine Einführung in die Erkenntnistheorie," Vorlesung Prag, 1932-1933 (Box 89, Folder 61)
  - "Philosopie des Raumes; Grundlagen der Geometrie": Vorlesung Wien, 1930-1932 (Box 89, Folder 62)
  - "Von Gott und Seele. Scheinfragen in Metaphysik und Theologie," Vortrag Verein Ernst Mach, 1929, 1929-1930 (Box 89, Folder 63)
  - "Neue Grundlegung der Logik" (Item 1), 1929 (Box 89, Folder 64a)
  - "Neue Grundlegung der Logik" (Item 2), 1929 (Box 89, Folder 64b)
  - "Die Quasizerlegung", 1922-1923 (Box 89, Folder 65)
  - International Encyclopedia of Unified Science, Vol. I, No. 3: Notes, Reviews, Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 89, Folder 66)
  - Carnap-Stegmüller: "Induktive Logik", 1956-1958 (Box 89, Folder 67)
  - "Logical Foundation of Probability," with Revisions, 1957-1962 (Box 89, Folder 68a)
  - "Logical Foundation of Probability," with Revisions, (Items 3-5), 1957-1962 (Box 89, Folder 68b)
  - "Logical Foundation of Probability," with Revisions, (Items 6-8), 1957-1962 (Box 89, Folder 68c)
  - "Logical Foundation of Probability," with Revisions, (Items 9-20), 1957-1962 (Box 89, Folder 68d)
  - "Inductive Logic and Inductive Intuition," Published London Lecture, 1965 (Box 89, Folder 69)
  - Seminar "Logical Modalities", 1946-1959 (Box 89, Folder 70)
  - "Sprache mit Prädikaten transfiniter Stufe", 1937 (Box 89, Folder 71)
  - "Deutschlands Niederlage: Sinnloses Schicksal oder Schuld?", 1918 (Box 89, Folder 72)
  - "Scipio: Dramatisches Schauspiel in 4 Aufzügen von Rudi Carnap", 1903 (?) (Box 89, Folder 73)
  - Brief an Pastor LeSeur, 1916-1917 (Box 89, Folder 74)
  - "Notes for Symbolic Logic," Typescript Chicago, 1937 (Box 89, Folder 75)
- Correspondence with Individuals, Organizations, and Institutions, 1930-1970; XVII.
  The correspondence in this series is divided into 4 subseries. Subseries 1 represents correspondence with individuals, subseries 2 with institutions and organizations; subseries 3 features correspondence with the National Science Foundation, and subseries 4 contains correspondence and manuscript drafts relating to the publication of Carnap's Schilpp autobiography.
  - Correspondence with Individuals, 1.
    - Quine, W.V., 1957-1959, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Reichenbach, Mia, 1962-1963 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Rand, Dr. Rose, 1953-1955 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Riska, Augustin, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Robinson, Abraham, Notes, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 1962-1969 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Schulz, Dietrich, 1965 and 1968 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Seeger, Raymond J., 1966-1967 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Simon, Herbert, 1958 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Statera, Gianni, 1966-1967 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Stegmüller, Wolfgang, 1966-1970 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Stegmüller, Wolfgang, 1952-1965 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Stein, Howard, 1954-1967 (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Suszko, Roman, 1958 (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Tarski, Alfred, Notes, 1930-1933, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Tarski and Quine: Finitism Discussion (Items 1-10), 1940-1941 (Box 90, Folder 16a)
    - Tarski and Quine: Finitism Discussion (Items 11-17), 1941 (Box 90, Folder 16b)
    - Tarski and Quine: Finitism Discussion (Items 18-23), 1941 (Box 90, Folder 16c)
    - Tarski and Quine: Finitism Discussion (Items 24-30), 1941 (Box 90, Folder 16d)
    - Tennessen, Herman, 1960-1961 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Tondl, Ladislav, 1956-1969 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Waismann, Friedrich, 1938 (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Weizäcker, Carl Friedrich von, 1966 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Wilkinson, Dr. John, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Winnie, John, 1967 and 1970 (Box 90, Folder 22)
    - Wisdom, J.O., 1966 and 1970 (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - von Wright, Georg Henrik, 1962-1969 (Box 90, Folder 24)
    - Addresses, 1935 (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Altersheime Deutschland, 1967 and 1970 (Box 90, Folder 26)
    - Distribution Lists of Reprints, 1961-1970 (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - Distribution of Reprints: Letters, 1961-1964 (Box 90, Folder 28)
    - Distribution Lists of Reprints (Items 1-18), 1952-1963 (Box 90, Folder 29a)
    - Distribution Lists of Reprints (Items 19-31), 1945-1952 (Box 90, Folder 29b)
    - Filing System, 1954-1968 (Box 90, Folder 30)
    - Books: Biographies and Autobiographies, Clippings, 1966 (Box 90, Folder 31)
    - Books: Fiction, Clipping, 1964 (Box 90, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence with Institutions and Organizations, 2.
    - Academie Internationale de Philosophies des Sciences, Bruxelles, 1962-1970 (Box 90, Folder 33)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1963-1969 (Box 90, Folder 34)
    - California State Employees' Association, C.S.E.A., 1964-1969 (Box 90, Folder 35)
    - American Association on Emeriti, 1964 (Box 90, Folder 36)
    - Emeriti Association UCLA, 1967 and 1970 (Box 90, Folder 37)
    - American Philosophical Aassociation, 1962-1971 (Box 90, Folder 38)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1960-1970 (Box 90, Folder 39)
    - Philosophy of Science Association, 1965-1968 (Box 90, Folder 40)
    - Russell Peace Foundation, 1961-1970 (Box 90, Folder 41)
    - World Condominium Club, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 42)
    - Associated Students Bookstore, 1969-1970 (Box 90, Folder 43)
    - World Citizens League, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 44)
    - World Constitution Convention, 1966-1968 (Box 90, Folder 45)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, SANE, 1966-1970 (Box 90, Folder 46)
    - A.P.A. Committee on Freedom for Latin-American Philosophers, Correspondence, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 47)
    - New York Review of Books, 1969 (Box 90, Folder 48)
    - Mexico, Cuts from Periodicals, 1967 and 1970 (Box 90, Folder 49)
    - Mexico Report by R.C., 1970 (Box 90, Folder 50)
    - Mexican Jail Report, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 51)
    - Europäisches Forum Alpbach, 1965-1969 (Box 90, Folder 52)
    - Tagung Alpbach, 1964 (Box 90, Folder 53)
    - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1964-1970 (Box 90, Folder 54)
    - Amsterdam Congress, 1966-1967 (Box 90, Folder 55)
    - University of Minnesota-UCLA Colloquia on Mind-Body Problem, 1965-1966 (Box 90, Folder 56)
    - Conference on Inductive Logic at Princeton, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 57)
    - International Congress for Philosophy of Science, Stanford, 1960, 1959-1961 (Box 90, Folder 58)
    - Internationaler Kongress für Philosophie, Wien 1968, 1967-1968 (Box 90, Folder 59)
    - Congreso International de Filosofía Mexico 1963, 1962-1963 (Box 90, Folder 60)
    - Harvard Project Physics, 1966 (Box 90, Folder 61)
    - Minnesota Center Conference "Physicalism", 1954-1957 (Box 90, Folder 62)
    - Minnesota Center, Memoranda, 1949-1960 (Box 90, Folder 63)